

Energetic recruiting professional with over seven years of experience. Skilled at matching employers' needs with the skills and goals of new hires and candidates for internal promotion. Fluent in industry-standard recruiting software. Able to take a company's culture into consideration while assessing potential employees.

Professional Experience

Talent Recruiter

Salient Software, Durham, NC November 2015 - Present

- · Discuss and develop job descriptions and postings with senior management
- Manage job postings, often 10 or more at a single time, and monitor responses from applicants
- Coordinate and conduct interviews that take place over the phone, on-site, or via videoconferencing
- Closely evaluate the abilities and cultural fit of potential hires who progress to later rounds of the selection process, then make recommendations to senior management
- Prepare and review relevant documentation, including offer letters

Junior HR Associate

Saratoga Solutions, Durham, NC July 2012 - October 2015

- Oversaw the adoption of Breezy recruiting software, streamlining the hiring process
- · Conducted initial background checks on applicants
- Increased the one-year retention rate of new hires by 25%

100 First Street, Durham, NC 27715
a. a 1I wood@emai I .com (123)456-7890

Education

Bachelor of Science in Human Resources Management Durham School Of Business, Durham, NC September 2008 - June 2012

Key Skills

- · Written and verbal communication
- Evaluation of potential and current employees' career paths and desires
- · Use of Microsoft Office suite
- Use of Breezy, 2ipRecruiter, Oracle Cloud, and other talent-recruitment and management platforms

Certifications

- Professional Credential in Human
 Resources, HR Certification Board,
 2018
- Certificate of Talent Evaluation, HR Society, 2020